<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Reading - 30TipsAndQuotes</string>
    <string name="set_times">Set times</string>
    <string name="set_times_tip">You should have a few set times during every day when you’ll read for at least 5–10 minutes. These are times that you will read no matter what — triggers that happen each day. For example, make it a habit to read during breakfast and lunch (and even dinner if you eat alone). And if you also read every time you’re sitting on the can, and when you go to bed, you now have four times a day when you read for 10 minutes each — or 40 minutes a day. That’s a great start, and by itself would be an excellent daily reading habit. But there’s more you can do.</string>
    <string name="set_times_quote">\"Books don\'t change people; paragraphs do, sometimes even sentences.\" - John Piper, A Godward Life</string>
    <string name="always_carry_a_book">Always carry a book</string>
    <string name="always_carry_a_book_tip">Wherever you go, take a book with you. If there is a time when you have to wait (like at a doctor’s office or at the DMV), whip out your book and read. Great way to pass the time.</string>
    <string name="always_carry_a_book_quote">\"Books are a uniquely portable magic.\" - Stephen King, On Writing</string>
    <string name="use_audiobooks">Use Audiobooks</string>
    <string name="use_audiobooks_tip">If reading print is difficult for you, audiobooks can be a game-changer. You can listen to audiobooks while doing other activities, such as walking, cooking, or cleaning, making it a more accessible and enjoyable experience. Many libraries offer audiobooks for free, and there are also paid services like Audible that offer a vast selection of audiobooks.</string>
    <string name="use_audiobooks_quote">\"A book is a garden, an orchard, a storehouse, a party, a company by the way, a counselor, a multitude of counselors.\" – Charles Baudelaire</string>
    <string name="choose_books_of_interest">Choose Books That Interest You</string>
    <string name="choose_books_of_interest_tip">One of the biggest barriers to enjoying reading is choosing books that you are not interested in. When selecting a book, consider your personal preferences, hobbies, and interests. If you are a fan of mystery and suspense, try picking up a thriller novel. If you love history, consider a biography or a historical fiction novel. By selecting books that speak to your interests, you are more likely to be engaged and invested in the story.</string>
    <string name="choose_books_of_interest_quote">\"If you don’t like to read, you haven’t found the right book.\" – J.K. Rowling</string>
    <string name="make_a_list">Make a list</string>
    <string name="make_a_list_tip">Keep a list of all the great books you want to read. You can keep this in your journal, in a pocket notebook, on your personal home page, on your personal wiki, wherever. Be sure to add to it whenever you hear about a good book, online or in person. Keep a running list, and cross out the ones you read.</string>
    <string name="make_a_list_quote">\"The more that you read, the more things you will know. The more that you learn, the more places you’ll go.\" -Dr. Seuss, I Can Read With My Eyes Shut</string>
    <string name="adjust_environment">Adjust Your Reading Environment</string>
    <string name="adjust_environment_tip">Sometimes the reading environment can be a hindrance to enjoying reading. Find a quiet, well-lit area with minimal distractions. If you’re reading print, consider using a book stand or a book light to make reading more comfortable. If you’re reading on a screen, adjust the font size and background color to reduce eye strain.</string>
    <string name="adjust_environment_quote">\"I like libraries. It makes me feel comfortable and secure to have walls of words, beautiful and wise, all around me. I always feel better when I can see that there is something to hold back the shadows.\" - Roger Zelazny, Nine Princes in Amber</string>
    <string name="reduce_tv_internet">Reduce television/Internet</string>
    <string name="reduce_tv_internet_tip">If you really want to read more, try cutting back on TV or Internet consumption. This may be difficult for many people. Still, every minute you reduce of Internet/TV, you could use for reading. This could create hours of book reading time.</string>
    <string name="reduce_tv_internet_quote">\"I find television very educating. Every time somebody turns on the set, I go into the other room and read a book.\" - Groucho Marx</string>
    <string name="take_breaks">Take Breaks</string>
    <string name="take_breaks_tip">Reading for extended periods can be tiring and overwhelming. Taking short breaks can help you stay refreshed and engaged. Consider setting a timer for every 20–30 minutes to take a quick break, stretch, and recharge your mind.</string>
    <string name="take_breaks_quote">\"In the case of good books, the point is not to see how many of them you can get through, but rather how many can get through to you.\" - Mortimer J. Adler</string>
    <string name="join_a_book_club">Join a Book Club</string>
    <string name="join_a_book_club_tip">Joining a book club can be a fun and engaging way to share your love of reading with others. Book clubs offer an opportunity to discuss books, share opinions, and gain new insights into literature. Additionally, they can offer a sense of community and belonging, which can make reading more enjoyable.</string>
    <string name="join_a_book_club_quote">\"What really knocks me out is a book that, when you’re all done reading it, you wish the author that wrote it was a terrific friend of yours and you could call him up on the phone whenever you felt like it. That doesn’t happen much, though.\" - J.D. Salinger, The Catcher in the Rye</string>
    <string name="keep_a_log">Keep a log</string>
    <string name="keep_a_log_tip">This log should have not only the title and author of the books you read, but the dates you start and finish them if possible. Even better, put a note next to each with your thoughts about the book. It is extremely satisfying to go back over the log after a couple of months to see all the great books you’ve read.</string>
    <string name="keep_a_log_quote">\"When I look back, I am so impressed again with the life-giving power of literature. If I were a young person today, trying to gain a sense of myself in the world, I would do that again by reading, just as I did when I was young.\" - Maya Angelou</string>
    <string name="read_fun_books">Read fun and compelling books</string>
    <string name="read_fun_books_tip">Find books that really grip you and keep you going. Even if they aren’t literary masterpieces, they make you want to read — and that’s the goal here. After you have cultivated the reading habit, you can move on to more difficult stuff, but for now, go for the fun, gripping stuff.</string>
    <string name="read_fun_books_quote">\"That’s the thing about books. They let you travel without moving your feet.\" - Jhumpa Lahiri, The Namesake</string>
    <string name="make_it_pleasurable">Make it pleasurable</string>
    <string name="make_it_pleasurable_tips">Make your reading time your favorite time of day. Have some good tea or coffee while you read, or another kind of treat. Get into a comfortable chair with a good blanket. Read during sunrise or sunset, or at the beach.</string>
    <string name="make_it_pleasurable_quotes">\"Rainy days should be spent at home with a cup of tea and a good book.\" - Bill Watterson</string>
    <string name="blog_it">Blog it</string>
    <string name="blog_it_tip">One of the best ways to form a habit is to put it on your blog. If you don’t have one, create one. It’s free. Have your family go there and give you book suggestions and comment on the ones you’re reading. It keeps you accountable for your goals.</string>
    <string name="blog_it_quote">\"Ah, how good it is to be among people who are reading.\" - Rainer Maria Rilke</string>
    <string name="set_a_high_goal">Set a high goal</string>
    <string name="set_a_high_goal_tip">Tell yourself that you want to read 50 books this year (or some other number like that). Then set about trying to accomplish it. Just be sure you’re still enjoying the reading though — don’t make it a rushed chore.</string>
    <string name="set_a_high_goal_quote">\"Read a lot. Expect something big, something exalting or deepening from a book. No book is worth reading that isn’t worth re-reading.\" - Susan Sontag</string>
    <string name="have_reading_hour_day">Have a reading hour or reading day</string>
    <string name="have_reading_hour_day_tip">If you turn off the TV or Internet in the evening, you could have a set hour (perhaps just after dinner) when you and maybe all the members of your family read each night. Or you could do a reading day, when you (and again, your other family members if you can get them to join you) read for practically the whole day. It’s super fun.</string>
    <string name="have_reading_hour_day_quote">\"Let’s be reasonable and add an eighth day to the week that is devoted exclusively to reading.\" - Lena Dunham</string>
    <string name="day_1">Day 1</string>
    <string name="day_2">Day 2</string>
    <string name="day_3">Day 3</string>
    <string name="day_4">Day 4</string>
    <string name="day_5">Day 5</string>
    <string name="day_6">Day 6</string>
    <string name="day_7">Day 7</string>
    <string name="day_8">Day 8</string>
    <string name="day_9">Day 9</string>
    <string name="day_10">Day 10</string>
    <string name="day_11">Day 11</string>
    <string name="day_12">Day 12</string>
    <string name="day_13">Day 13</string>
    <string name="day_14">Day 14</string>
    <string name="day_15">Day 15</string>
    <string name="day_16">Day 16</string>
    <string name="day_17">Day 17</string>
    <string name="day_18">Day 18</string>
    <string name="day_19">Day 19</string>
    <string name="day_20">Day 20</string>
    <string name="day_21">Day 21</string>
    <string name="day_22">Day 22</string>
    <string name="day_23">Day 23</string>
    <string name="day_24">Day 24</string>
    <string name="day_25">Day 25</string>
    <string name="day_26">Day 26</string>
    <string name="day_27">Day 27</string>
    <string name="day_28">Day 28</string>
    <string name="day_29">Day 29</string>
    <string name="day_30">Day 30</string>
    <string name="expand_button_content_description">See more or less information for this day</string>
</resources>